[Music]
Hey, good morning, John. You're watching
the program with Ted Rall and John
Kiriakou. It's Wednesday, December 10th,
2025. Thanks for joining us. Good to see
you, John. Good to see you, Ted. I like
your shirt. Oh, thank you. I decided to
dress up for today's program.
So, no no casual Wednesday, only casual
Friday. Um but I can't promise this will
be an ongoing trend.
Um so,
uh we are we have some business some
housekeeping to keep to take care of and
then we'll get to the show. As always,
please chime in with your questions and
comments on YouTube and Rumble if you're
watching live. If you're streaming us
later, thank you nevertheless for
joining us. We're here Monday through
Friday 9:00 a.m. Eastern time if that
suits for live and then you can interact
with us. Speaking with about
interaction. So, next 2 days,
let me explain what's going on. So,
John, you're out tomorrow, Thursday.
Friday,
so tomorrow we we have a live show.
Robbie will be Sorry, Scott Stantis of
the Chicago Tribune will be will be
filling in. Not to say that Robbie might
not chime in as well as usual.
And then on Friday, we're going to try
something brand new here for the show
and I'm looking forward to this as a
former talk radio guy. We're going to be
doing talk radio. We're going to So,
we're going to have a Discord link.
We're going to do the show.
Robbie's going to explain how all this
works in about 10 or 15 minutes. So,
stay tuned for that. But basically,
you'll be able to call in like we're
old-fashioned like Rush Limbaugh, Dr.
Laura Schlessinger type call and we'll
have a little back and forth and you
know, but we're going to I'm sure have
more than one or two people who want to
do this. So, we're going to keep the
calls short and quick and and moving.
There could be tech glitches. We tried
this a little bit on TMI yesterday and
it was kind of like iffy, but we think
we have it wrinkle worked out and ironed
out the wrinkles. So,
Friday is an all call-in show.
We will obviously chime in on the news
of the day, but that's basically it.
Robbie will explain the logistics.
Today we're talking about Trump's big
interview with Politico where he was
dissing the Europeans not for the first
time, but this was a more interesting
interview than usual. Also, Ukraine
looks like they're finally this
democracy is finally going to have some
elections.
Interestingly enough, that's due to
pressure from the president. Um
Russia, we'll talk about this. Russia
has apparently
has a lot of spies in Mexico
and the US has complained about it, but
the Mexicans basically aren't doing
anything about it. That according to the
New York Times anyway.
The Afghan guy who was accused of
shooting two national guardsmen in
Washington, one of whom died,
was a veteran of a CIA-trained zero unit
under the Afghan occupation government
from and turns out he is just one of
many people who suffered mental health
breakdowns because of the way they were
mistreated and ignored after they
arrived in the United States.
And so I have thoughts. I'm sure you'll
have thoughts, John.
Um
You John, you brought up this important
point. Big election in Miami, a runoff
election saw a giant sweep. 60% of the
vote went to the Democrat.
And so basically urban America is going
blue. And finally, last but not least,
the New York Times has an exclusive
report that says
that talked about the internal workings
of the White House and how they're
trying to deal with the survivors of the
alleged boat drug boat attacks.
They're kind of a major sticky wiki that
kind of harkens back to the way that
enemy combatants were treated and when
during the war on terror. It's kind of
like what do you do with these people?
And there was thoughts of sending them
to that gulag prison in El Salvador.
They decided not to go with that. So,
John, what's your
what's your what's your flavor for the
first topic? Let's talk about Miami just
to get it out of the way. So,
the Democrat won yesterday in the Miami
mayoral race. That initially sounds like
no big deal. It's a big city. Big cities
always elect Democrats. Not Miami.
Miami is a solidly Republican city. It's
always been Republican and this is the
first Democrat to be elected mayor of
Miami in 30 years. That's right. And the
race wasn't close. And not only was it
not close,
Trump campaigned for the Republican.
Senator
what's-his-face Scott
campaigned for the Republican. Scott.
And Rick Scott, thanks. And
Ron DeSantis campaigned for the
Republican.
And he still lost.
So, man, if if the Virginia and and New
Jersey gubernatorial races didn't
constitute a glaring flashing red light
for the Republicans,
this ought to because nationally they're
in trouble right now. And with these
redistricts with the the redistricting
plans that they're pushing across the
country, they're diluting Republican
congressional districts and risking a
real wave come next November.
Yeah, Republicans are spinning this as
Miami-Dade has always leaned blue.
That's just That's what you say, John.
>> not true.
>> That's not true cuz especially all the
anti-Castro Cubans and
>> That's right. That was the major major
tipping point. And as you say,
I felt I thought of you because the By
the way, the Republican candidate was
not some wanker.
He was he was a very respectable solid
candidate. And Donald Trump doesn't like
to endorse even Republicans
if he doesn't think they're going to
win. So, this came as a surprise to the
GOP.
You know, just for the record here, I
lean Higgins is not like a progressive
Democrat in the
Mamdani
form. But to me, the real takeaway here
is
it's two takeaways. First of all, urban
America is pretty much done with the
Republicans for the for the time being.
And then the other thing was okay, this
is a harbinger. I mean, you know, we're
always trying to read tea leaves and I
think it tends to be overstated a lot of
times, but you can't ignore a solid 100%
trend in favor of one party. And that's
what we have right now. I mean, I think
the Republicans are going into disaster
zone next year.
I saw the president's speech. I believe
he was in Pennsylvania. Yeah, your home
state. And he and he was saying
basically arguing that the economy had
recovered and that Pennsylvanians and I
guess and Americans by extension are
doing great now.
You know, you and I talked about this.
We will talk about it again. That's
political malpractice. You never Even
Let's just say you and I were the
president and vice president and we were
you know, we thought the economy was
rocking and that every But you don't
tell the people if they if they're
grouchy and they don't think they're
broke, then they're broke and you have
to come to where the people are. Ted,
yesterday, and I know we're going to get
to this in a second. Yesterday
Trump gave an interview to Politico
magazine in which he said that this was
the strongest economy in American
history, which is
so ridiculous it doesn't even it doesn't
even warrant a response. And he also
said that when he
took office the second time, the country
was struggling with his his words, the
worst inflation in American history.
Mhm. What? That's Jimmy Carter. Yeah.
Or at least in the in the modern era. In
the modern era, that's right. I mean,
the 19 Let's not get started on the 19th
century.
>> No, it was depression after depression
in the
in the 19th century. Yeah, the But like
No, I mean, he always talks about that.
I mean, you know, look, you always The
truth is it's very smart to talk about
the something something in American
history to a country that doesn't know
anything about history. So, it's
Exactly. It works. People are like, "Oh,
okay. Well, you know, he's he's the
president. He said it. It must mean it's
true."
>> I've told you in the past I I watch
uh Tik Tok videos when I'm laying in bed
at night.
My attention span by the end of the day
is short and I go to sleep with these.
And there's this young guy who just
stands in Times Square or
at Hollywood and Highland and just asks
people questions. So, he'll say, "Who
won the Civil War?"
And they'll answer like
"We did." Oh my god.
>> Or
"Russia."
You know, stuff like that. That's
America. Americans don't know.
Yeah, there's a you know, there I mean,
you The thing is that never gets old
that stick.
You know, I think Was it Letterman or or
Leno who used to do the same thing?
>> out on the street. I think it was
Letterman. It might have been Letterman.
And and like the There's also um
This Ain't No Heartland was this Bush
era documentary where these Dutch
filmmakers did the same thing and they
they they went all over the country and
talked to Bush voters.
At one point they go to like a shopping
mall and outdoor shopping mall. And you
can tell these are well-off people,
okay? And so this is to say, these are
not like homeless derelict crackheads.
These are people driving like really
nice cars that like I couldn't afford.
Right.
And like Benz and stuff. And they show
them a map of the world. And and they're
like, "Oh, what country should we attack
next?" And no one says by the way, "Why
would we want to attack a country?" That
just doesn't And they like they look at
the map, but the names of the countries
aren't written on the countries. And so
they're like oh uh I think that one the
guy points to Africa. It's like oh what
country is that? Oh, that's Iran. And
it's like oh so or of course he says
Iran. He's like
Iran. So it's like uh okay oh so why
should we attack them? And he goes their
attitude.
And it's it's it's stuff like that. I
mean, you know, that's America. It's
America. I mean, it is. I don't think we
really deserve democracy really.
Um we're we're ill-equipped to manage
it.
You Tocqueville would agree for sure.
Yeah, I think so. Um so okay so like
yeah so
so basically um I thought of you because
Emilio Gonzalez who's the former city
manager who lost and had been endorsed
by top Republicans like DeSantis and
Trump.
Um he had his victory I mean he by the
way he he conceded extremely graciously
and uh and promised to help the the new
mayor-elect uh and and stand behind her
you know in a in a better way than say
Andrew Cuomo did in New York um
or Eric Adams. But
uh I I thought of you because his party
was at a his victory party was at a
Greek restaurant and they broke plates
as a as as catharsis.
You know, that's actually illegal now in
Greece. It has been since the 90s.
But you can do it in all the Greek
nightclubs in in Astoria. Why is it
illegal? Cuz it cuz if there's lead in
the plates or something? What? No, as as
my dad and your dad undoubtedly used to
say you're going to put an eye out.
Pass out safety glasses to all the
patrons.
Um that's pretty funny. All right, let's
do some questions, shall we? Um
thank you so $1 contribution. Thank you
so much. Just wanted to remind you guys
you can always contribute through
YouTube and Rumble. And frankly, yeah,
we're begging cuz we're broke as [__]
So seriously, whatever you can do
all right. Favorite Christmas movies.
Mine is Charlie Brown Christmas and the
year without Santa because of Heat and
and Miser. So I just watched my favorite
Christmas movie for the umpteenth time.
It's Bad Santa.
Bad Santa's a terrific movie.
That's a terrific movie. Although
nothing touches Home Alone. Home Alone
is a timeless classic. No question. I
the first time I ever saw Home Alone was
on a flight from London to Washington.
I'd been overseas doing something. I
don't even remember what.
And I was laughing so much that the
flight attendant came up and asked if I
was okay.
Like you're suffering from this is funny
as movie I've ever seen.
Hypoxia
or hysteria induced hypoxia induced
hysteria.
Oh my god. No
I mean you know by the way in French the
name for Home Alone I I know cuz I was
in France when the movie was
my mom she wanted to take the plane.
Mom, I missed the plane.
Really?
Home Alone just seems By the way you
could do it in French. Yeah,
I love I love I love my zone to sell.
We would be fine. I I don't understand.
Anyway, oh my god. Nicholas Franco's
question for you John. Is it true that
the CIA along with Turkish intelligence
tried to kill a Greek intelligence
officer in 1999 outside the Greek
Embassy in Nairobi? I believe you know
his name.
I in fact he's a good friend of mine
Savas Kalenderidis. No, they did not.
You would say. No.
He's he's an absolutely lovely man. He's
a national hero in Greece. I thoroughly
enjoy his friendship. He's
He's just a great guy and he has an
awesome YouTube podcast. Sometimes as
many as four times a day. And any
anytime something hits the news that's
even slightly interesting to him, he'll
jump on YouTube and do a video.
So if you're interested and you speak
Greek because he doesn't speak a word of
English Savas Kalenderidis.
No, they didn't try to kill him. Savas
was involved in an operation
to um
to help save protect
Abdullah Ocalan the founder of the PKK.
And
the Greeks became aware I'm sorry the
Turks became aware that he was in the
Greek Embassy in Nairobi
and they worked with Kenyan intelligence
to
divert part of his motorcade and they
grabbed him and turned him over to the
Turks.
John, let's get back to the Miami thing
before we answer a few more questions. I
mean, what do you think happened there?
I mean, do you think this was a matter
of
low My theory is always these days that
your biggest challenge is
is motivating your base and that maybe
the Republican base isn't that excited
about Trump / DeSantis and / the GOP as
they used to be
or is it just the particularities of
these two candidates? Is it a Miami
thing? I mean, what do you think you
know? I think that it's at least in part
that
people are not liking this second Trump
administration probably for economic
reasons. But I'll tell you where I think
the Democrats are going to blow it
because the Democrats always blow it.
They do. And Trump knows it and he
talked about it in his political
Politico interview. The Democrats are
going to blow it by focusing on social
issues.
And
people don't like this trans stuff
forced down their throats. No, they
don't. They just don't like it.
And it shouldn't The thing is even
people who are very pro LGBT QIA plus
element of P are are they they're not
it's not a top issue for them. It's
right? There's like sort of like caring
about like we're going to talk about the
boat strikes. Most Americans disapprove
of the killing of the boat strikes. But
they don't really care. And that's
something we don't talk about much is
like what's the top issues that are
motivating people? Even people who are
like I love trans people. I want I don't
want any I only want the best for them.
But they don't want it to be a top
priority over say the economy. No,
that's right. And you know a lot of my
gay friends and maybe it's more a factor
of of the fact that they're baby
boomers.
But a lot of my gay friends say that
most trans people do not necessarily
identify as gay. And so why are they
LGBTQIAD
plus whatever
in the first place when they're actually
turning public opinion against the LGBT
community? Yeah, there's some major
rifts there, right? Between like for
example the radical feminists and the
and the trans women the
trans-exclusionary feminists the TERFs
radical feminists
and all that. And I mean I think in the
early days of when it was just LGBT
I remember when it was just LGB. Yeah.
And then too. And when it was just LGB
you could sort Even then there were
rifts, right? I knew lots of gay people
who hated bi people. And they were like
you have to choose your team. You're not
allowed to be omnivorous.
And then so the T's you know I mean I
understand the whole urge to to build
these alliances. But the truth is that's
a very uncomfortable big tent. You know,
Philip Blair 9511 just posted in the
chat Cuba is great at supporting queer
families. That's true. I was shocked
when I was in Cuba
what was it two years ago I guess
at how strong the gay community is there
and how many
how many government programs are
available to them. It was really
something.
Yeah, as Lisa Mojica says in YouTube
it's the hierarchy of needs and I think
we don't talk about that in in American
the coverage of American news politics
very much. Not American question as
Freud 6624 says is the DNC the GOP
counterpart in the other side.
Um
repeat that. This is a hard one to read.
Is the DNC the GOP counterpart
in the other side?
No, the D GOP is just a nickname for the
Republican Party. The DNC is the
Democratic National Committee which is
the governing body of the Democratic
Party. It's just the same. And the
Republican Party equivalent of the DNC
is the RNC the Republican National
Committee. Um yeah, important question
indeed. Cooper Duper 23 I think the
regular American voter is sick of the
status quo. I wouldn't be surprised if a
lot of sticks and seats flip. I don't
think it has anything to do with party
anymore. We're figuring out who is
bought.
I don't think you're figuring They're
all bought. So I think what's happening
is that people are frustrated. They have
two shitty choices and when they're
pissed they vote against the incumbent.
Yeah, that's it. You know,
it really is about the economy. It's
always about the economy. It's about
people's well-being and their families'
well-being.
These other issues are extraneous. They
only distract.
And I don't know why
neither the Republicans nor the
Democrats get it. The Republicans got it
last time. To your point John, you know,
the exception is when the economy is
humming.
You know, remember the mid-90s when that
was the biggest economic expansion in US
history at least until that point.
That's right. And
those wedge issues that
the toe-sucking guy
you know you know what I'm talking
about. Um
uh
the pollster the genius pollster. I I
met him at his at his house.
He's a good He's a good political Dick
Morris. Great political writer. Yeah.
Anyway, Dick Morris they came up with
all those wedge issues in the mid-90s
like flag burning and you know gays in
the military and all that stuff.
The gays in the military kind of ran
against Clinton, but flag burning and
God, like oh oh
sister sister soldier
all that symbolic crap at works if the
economy is moving in the right
direction, but if it's not Yeah.
>> That is right. Um okay, so
>> Hey, I'm dying to talk even if if it's
just for a minute. I'm dying to talk
about about Trump's comments on Ilhan
Omar. Okay, let's do it. Listen to this
quote.
I love this Ilhan Omar, whatever the
hell her name is with her little turban.
I love her. She comes in, she does
nothing but [__] She's always
complaining. Comes from her country
where I mean it's considered about the
worst country in the world. We got to
get her the hell out of here. She
married her brother in order to get in,
right? She married her brother to get
in. Therefore, she's here illegally.
Send her back.
Like that's the best quote I've ever
seen.
It's so it's free association. Do you
remember John after the Watergate tape
transcripts were were released, some
famous poet like set a lot of the
transcripts of the of Nixon talking to
poetry?
And and released them it's like and it
was called like the poetry of Richard
Milhous Nixon. Oh my God, I I did not I
did not see that
at all.
>> sounds like that.
It could totally yeah. That stuff could
totally be set to poetry. Yeah, I agree.
I agree, it could. Yeah, this uh this
idea that she married her brother
has been running around
Republican circles since she was first
elected. She didn't marry her brother.
Um she she married a guy or she she
married a guy in a in a Muslim ceremony.
His name was Ahmed Abdisalan Hirsi. They
had two kids, they separated.
In 2009 she married a Brit named Ahmed
Nur Said Elmi.
They separated in 2011. She reunited
with the first guy in 2012. She divorced
Elmi and remarried
the first guy.
Well, that's a little
>> That's a little bit Liz Taylor and
Richard Burtony. Yeah, it very much. But
she's not married to her brother. She's
never been married to her brother.
>> how these theory how these things get
out. And by the way, Republicans are not
unique in having these strange
conspiracy theories.
Democrats do it, too. They do it, too.
Um US XXXArod21,
thanks for the two bucks. Do we think
that this makes means Democrats will
lean into the economy or go back to
social issues that the majority of the
country doesn't care about? Not holding
out hope for them. That's the question.
Are they smart enough
to be able to read the writing on the
wall that it's about the economy? No. Or
are they going to try and force all
these stupid social issues down our
throats? If we're look honestly, John,
if they did social issues at least
they'd be doing issues. I mean, you
know, I hear them talking the Democrats
recognize they have a problem. They
can't just be against Trump, but they
don't they still can't articulate or
won't articulate what they're for and I
think it's because they can't agree on
anything. Um and um but basically they
have terrible messaging. They have no
leadership. Mama Bear Pelosi's gone.
There's no one knocking heads and saying
like listen all you [__] this is
what we're going to say. Here's our
talking points. So I mean you know,
Hakeem Jeffries is like more useless
than useless. So there's I I think
there's just no
Um
I think they're going to they're going
to [__] it up. I mean, no I think right
now they're counting on a sense of
betrayal on the part of the GOP who will
sit enough Republican voters will sit on
their hands and not vote.
That's the key right there. It's all
about turnout. Yeah. The Democrats are
more are more motivated. So they will
turn out next year. I don't know how
federalized the election will be like
the way Newt Gingrich successfully did
in '94 with the Republican Revolution.
Yeah, that was brilliant. Absolutely.
And I'm surprised nobody tries to
replicate it.
Um it's kind of like dude, you know,
it's it's it's like Howard Dean and his
50 state print strategy. No one ever
tried to replicate. Again, brilliant.
That was the fallout between Hillary
Clinton and um
what's his name from New Orleans uh who
said it's the economy, stupid.
>> Oh um Carville. Carville yeah, James
Carville. James Carville
was
the one who came up with the 50 state
strategy in the '90s because it had
worked so well for the Democrats in the
'60s. The Democrats won Senate seats in
North Dakota, South Dakota in in both of
those cases all four Senate seats.
Idaho, Montana, Wyoming, Oklahoma. I
mean, there were viable Democratic Party
structures in those states.
And then
the Democrats just said, "Nah, we're not
going to do that anymore.
>> focus on the Electoral College map.
>> Yeah, we'll just focus on the Electoral
College. We're not going to try to build
local and state party structures to
support candidates for state legislature
or for Almost gutted that farm system.
>> Gutted it and the Democrats have been
paying the price ever since. They have.
And the other thing is even if you're
only looking at national races, which is
dumb, but let's just say cuz where did
Barack Obama come from, right? He was a
wet behind the ears local Illinois dude.
But the um
the thing is that the Republican I mean
the the Democratic Party even if like
the reason you campaign in all 50 states
is even in the states that you're going
to lose. Let's say you can't let's just
say for example, you campaign as a
Democrat in North Dakota, a state you're
probably not going to get as a
presidential candidate. But people turn
out and see you and they other people
who are watching back in say New Jersey
are watching on television and they're
seeing your appearances on the internet
and they like that you went to North
Dakota and maybe your brother lives in
North Dakota and says, "Oh, I went to
see that guy and he was great." And then
you vote for him. He doesn't, but you
get that vote in New Jersey that you
wouldn't have gotten. That's the point
of the 50 state You're exactly right.
You are exactly right. I mean, Donald
Trump
that's why Donald Trump like I remember
like when I I knew that Trump was going
to win in 2016 when Hillary Clinton
spent $5 million for her campaign
announcement and she built a stage in
the shape of the United States uh right
out right on the in Long Island City so
that she could use Manhattan as the
backdrop. By the way, Manhattan as a
backdrop not a good image for the entire
country. No. But $5 for the stage and
Donald Trump went and gave a speech in
some shitty elementary school in like
East in Scranton. And it's like, you
know what? You're both on television.
It's all the same.
And and Donald paid nothing except for
the flight the airfare to Scranton,
right? That's the difference and that's
why he won, you know, with a you know,
paying a couple million dollars to win
the presidency as opposed to $7 million
for Hillary Clinton.
Although she still complains about the
Russian about the about the Facebook
ads,
but whatever.
>> Yeah, yeah. It was the Facebook ads that
did her in, right. For sure. All right,
we'll do we have more questions coming
in, but let's in the meantime, let's
talk a little bit. I you know, this is
your obviously your bailiwick.
Um so according to uh this report uh in
the New York Times, um Mexic- Mexico is
harboring all sorts of GRU spies. Uh
apparently this is a tradition that goes
all the way back to the Cold War. Oh, it
goes way like to back to the '50s. And
they claim that it that like Mexico City
was like the Vienna of Latin America.
And um the US apparently under Biden
handed the Mexicans a big dossier with
you know, "Hey, here's all the people we
know who are spies in Mexico.
Uh you know, can you like kick them
out?" The Mexicans basically are
ignoring the whole thing. There's no
word on whether Trump administration
policy has changed or that they're
leaning on the Mexicans to try to do
anything. They might be, they might not
be. It just didn't say. Um but basically
I like the fact that the Mexican
officials said, "Well, we never got the
the dossier or it was too vague. Uh we
didn't really understand what you were
talking about or that it was lost." The
people like, "Huh?
We Someone recycled it, you know, we
were recycling. I don't know." So what
do you think about all this?
Well, it would be a normal
liaison event uh for the for the CIA to
pass the names of um
of KGB or GRU or SVR or whatever they're
calling themselves these days
uh to to a friendly liaison service.
They do that all the time. Um Mexico
City is particularly important because
it is a it is a hub of international
espionage. Like you said, Vienna,
London, Paris, Washington.
Why Mexico City?
Because um they spy on the United States
there. Our embassy is so gargantuan
in uh in Mexico City and so much happens
there
that they're targeting
the American embassy for the most part.
And what they what they probably are
doing what I would assume they're doing
>> Americans.
>> Right, no. No. No, it's trying to
recruit Mexicans who work inside the
American embassy. It's probably 75%
Mexicans that work in the American
embassy.
Right? Cuz you're not going to the head
of the motor pool is not going to be
American. The head of logistics is not
going to be American. But they have
access to information that if you put it
together like a puzzle, you can come up
with an entire picture. For example, um
I was working overseas. I won't say
where.
And the logistics guy had been in place
for 30 years. He was a local hire. 30
years he had been working for the
American Embassy and he's the guy that
make sure that your shipment of personal
household effects, you know, makes it
onto the ship in Baltimore, doesn't get
washed overboard in the Atlantic and
finally makes its way to to its
end destination.
Well,
once you once your stuff arrives,
he's the guy that arranges to have it
brought to your house. And then when he
calls you in the Embassy
from the second floor where he was based
and
you answer the phone, you know,
regional affairs or
training division or whatever that he
knows is a [__] assignment. There is
no such office. He reports back to his
people, his handler, "Hey, this guy
John, this new guy, he's CIA. I'm sure
of it." Because he's not in the
political section. It says in the
diplomatic list, political officer, he's
not a political officer. He didn't
answer the phone in the political
section.
You know, so they're able to they're
able to put little pieces of the puzzle
together. And when you have two, three,
five, 10 people inside the American
Embassy recruited because remember
they're making Mexican wages. They're
not being paid like Americans would be
paid. Right.
>> Russians are supplementing their incomes
to the tune of a few thousand That's
five, 10, that's that's meaningful a
month. Yeah.
>> Sure. John, we have an ad. Let me and
then we're going to bring in Robbie. Um
before but just very quickly, uh do you
think um it's true that the republic
that as being reported that the this
really ramped up after the uh
Russian-Ukrainian war started?
Absolutely. Um because basically we're
using Ukraine as a proxy to spy against
Russia right on its border and so the
Russians are kind of like let's turn
about is fair play. I I believe that's
that's the case, yes.
All right, now let's uh get to the ad.
Uh looking for smarter ways to browse
and enjoy your favorite content without
ads? Get the Perplexity Pl- Pro Bundle
with Rumble Premium for just $19.99 a
month when you stand when you sign up
before December 31st. Normally a $29.99
value, with Rumble Premium you'll get an
ad-free viewing experience across all
your devices and access to exclusive
premium content. No interruptions, just
the videos and streams you love anytime,
anywhere. Plus Perplexity Plo-
Perplexity Pro boosts your productivity
with unlimited research, unlimited
uploads, exclusive member perks and
access to the latest and most advanced
AI models for faster, smarter answers
every day. Save over 30% on this
powerful bundle, head to
rumble.com/premium before December 31st
to sign up and unlock your premium
experience. All right, we're going to
bring in Robbie West, our producer, uh
who's here thanks to your kind support,
uh kind listeners and viewers, to
explain
first of all, uh what we're going to be
doing on Friday.
Okay, so on Friday it's I'm really
looking forward to this. It's going to
be exciting. So we are going to be doing
a call-in show. So think Rush Limbaugh
without the windbaggery. That is exactly
what we're going to be doing.
So to make this work, I will post a link
in the chat to our Discord server.
And once you go in and uh we'll put
together a little screenshot or
something to put this so that way people
are able to see.
Uh you will see at the bottom of the
server, you're going to see a a a lobby,
a waiting room. You're going to just
park your cute little pixelated self
there.
I will then drag your cute little
pixelated self down to the call room
where you will be speaking with John and
Ted.
And uh you'll be able to ask your
questions and then after your question
is asked, I will then uh mute your
pixelated cute little butt so that way
someone else can come on in.
Now this is going to be a Rumble
exclusive.
Now
>> How people are people still going to
come to Rumble as usual to the channel
and then we're going to post the URL.
>> Yeah, I'll just post the link. They'll
click on it, join the server. I mean it
doesn't cost you a dime. It's completely
free. So this is So on Friday that means
there's no live show on YouTube. We will
post the recorded show on Fri- on
YouTube later in the day, but
>> Correct. But if you want to watch live
and comment and all that, you got to be
on Rumble. You got to be on Rumble and
the reason for that is this is not me
peeing on on YouTube.
It's because I cannot control what comes
out of your mouth. And YouTube is so
strict with their community guidelines
as somebody just goes on a full-on uh a
tear about a topic
against a protected group, you put
whatever there is that you want to put
in there,
YouTube will nuke the channel.
Rumble won't. So whenever I say that
Rumble is what allows us is what allows
this uh
this channel to speak freely,
that's not hyperbole. That's that's
true.
When YouTube when they demonetized John
and Ted, Rumble didn't.
And this right-wing platform paying the
bills of two lefties and I guess me now.
So Yeah, but I was
>> We're working on getting you over to the
left, Robbie.
Um well, I'm working on pulling y'all
over to the right. So maybe we'll meet
in the middle somewhere. Big tug-of-war.
Or on the other side. All right, Robbie.
I hope everyone understands that. Just
to re- reiterate, Friday, watch on
Rumble if you want to watch live at 9:00
a.m. You don't care about that, just you
can watch on YouTube later in the day, I
would say after 12:00 noon Eastern. Um
and uh but and and there will be a link
in the Rumble chat that Robbie will
post. Um I'm mostly going to post I'm
mostly going to post a link on YouTube
on a community tab so that way people
can just click on that. All you got to
do is just join my game.
>> warning, we're not going to be able to
talk to every if we get if a lot of
people want to do this, we won't be able
to take every call, but we will try to
take every call.
Correct.
Before Robbie gets off, too, there's
actually a question for him in the chat.
Did you see it? It was, "Robbie, do you
think that um
the the show Yellowstone?" Yeah,
Yellowstone has caused uh real estate
prices to uh to go up in Montana. Good
question. It didn't help anything. Yeah,
because most people don't think about
Montana. Right.
>> it's just it's just one of those
invisible flyover states that you may or
may not be able to find on a map. But
you know, people go and they see it,
they see how big it is, they see how
beautiful it is.
And then Yellowstone It is amazing. I I
love it there. I've been there enough
three times. I've taken my kids. It's
fantastic. Hey, I love it here. I moved
here in 2015 and or 2010 and it's home.
But now that being said,
Yellowstone did a very great way of kind
of showing Mont- showing Montana as this
paradise, which is always just true.
However, the winters here are brutally
cold. So Montana is closed. You do not
want to come here. It is cold.
>> Yeah. And there are large bitey animals.
Yes. Yeah, there there are. There was
actually a mountain lion walking down my
street yesterday. I saw one.
He's bring him in as a pet.
Take him to your company, to your cat.
Or anyway, beat him up.
Maybe. All right, Robbie, thank you very
much for all that and all right, well
and and we will
become All right, let's let's resume our
regular scheduled programming here.
Um okay, so anything else you want to
talk about about this? I mean so what do
you why do you think the Mexicans are
brushing off um
the Americans on this on this Mexico
City thing?
Yeah, I think honestly the Mexicans are
just sick and tired of us.
You know, we we probably when we passed
them the names, we probably also told
them, "Hey, wrap all these guys up and
expel them all from Mexico. We're
waiting."
And they probably told us
"Take care of your own problems.
We have other things to worry about."
Yeah. And and not to mention uh you
know,
when does the does even a Democratic
president ever go on TV and talk about
the great cooperation that the Mexican
government provides us with? Nobody. I
mean it's thankless, right? It's a
one-way You know, they're very
cooperative, but we treat them like we
treat we talk about them like dogs.
>> Yeah, we do. We do. We we treat them not
just like second-class citizens. We we
treat them as as coolies.
You know, and and they don't appreciate
it. So they just drag their feet.
They're like, "We're a real country. You
know, we have national pride. [__] you."
>> We're an important one.
Yeah, very important one. And actually a
a great country, too. I mean if if you
said, "Oh, I have to live in Mexico the
rest of my life," I'd be like, "Oh,
well, okay." Um not a bad thing at all.
Um
should we talk a little bit about the um
Trump's interview? Yeah, let's.
Let's. So Trump basically this is a
repeat of something he has said before.
Um he said that
basically this is a quote, "I think
their leaders are weak, but I also think
that they want to be so politically
correct. I don't I think they don't know
what to do." Um he basically this all
seems to be like centered around the
debate over Ukraine. The Europeans are
leaning on, you know, Trump wants the
the war to end. Um the the Europeans
clearly wanted it to go on. Um they they
uh and we can talk about why that might
be. But um
Trump's really signaled that he's almost
done with Ukraine. Um and he also said,
you know, Ukraine's not much of a
democracy if it doesn't have elections.
Finally, you you know, Zelenskyy, who
has claimed now for years that there's
no way to hold elections during a war,
suddenly miracu- miraculously says that
within the next three to six months
there will be elections. Um both
presidential and legislative. Bunch of
questions, John.
Is Zelenskyy going to keep his promise
about that? And if he does, what will
the results look like? And will he win
re-election?
I think he's done. I really do.
Um I think that
yeah, he he's going to keep his promise
because he has to keep his promise.
He can't continue to push back against
the pressure from the United States.
It's just too much. So, I I think that
there will be elections and I wouldn't
be surprised at all if
you know, he goes and casts his vote and
then drives to the airport and gets on a
plane and flies away. What if he pulls
an Eric Adams and decides just not to
run for re-election? And I think that's
also a definite possibility. I served my
country during war. I'm exhausted. It's
time to pass the torch. And Ted, you
know,
there's a lot of reporting about
cabinet members driving Bugattis and
Lamborghinis around Kiev. It's not cool.
The corruption is is now in your face
and somebody's going to have to answer
to it.
And and of course Zelenskyy and his
buddies are big beneficiaries of that
corruption.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so, I mean, here's the thing. I I got
to say
not for the last time, I agree with
President Trump about this. I mean, I
kind of don't know if the word weak is
the word I would say, but but like sort
of like um feckless um would be the word
I would say for President Macron and so
on. Like what are they on about? I mean,
like it's kind of like they they they're
clearly uh anyone with a brain can see
that you know, the outcome of this war
has fallen in favor of Russia. It's not
like the outcome's not likely to change
anytime soon. Um and and they want, you
know, Macron and these guys, they want
Zelenskyy to keep fighting.
But towards what end? I mean, they're
just going to lose even more territory.
At this point, I mean, I'd say the
sooner that if I'm the Ukrainians, the
sooner I negotiate the least bad deal
I'm going to get.
>> Exactly. And if the if the sticking
point really is just Kherson now, Mhm.
figure it out.
Right. Right. It's a negotiation. Yeah.
Maybe maybe Kherson can become like a
Danzig style like demilitarized nuclear
neutral city. That kind of thing. Fine
with me. Sure. Why not? I mean, I I I
mean, I could I I think you know,
looking for things that the the Russians
feel that they could agree to. Mhm.
Um
Okay.
>> I'm I'm like so many Americans. I I just
I'm tired of this. I'm tired of spending
all this money
for a for a never-ending war.
We're going to get nothing out of it.
It's time to move on.
Totally. All right. You should we do
some questions?
>> Yeah. Yeah, we're a little bit behind.
All right. Um all right. Thanks for your
patience, guys. Junaid Javid, thanks so
much for the $20 donation on Rumble.
Please keep Imran Khan in your thoughts.
Imran is still in illegal custody and
the field marshal in Pakistan has gone
full fascist.
Yeah, that's my understanding, too.
Yeah, that's I mean,
you know, the the thing is a lot of
prime ministers and former prime
ministers end up in prison in Pakistan.
You know what's never clear, John, is
what kind of conditions they're held
under. Right. Um you know, it's like it
seems like I mean, Pakistani prison
can't be that pleasant.
>> I I wouldn't want to be in I listen,
I've I've gone to many Pakistani prisons
because we were locking people up there.
I would never want to be incarcerated in
a single one of them. So, you don't
think there's any like uh VIP uh lounge
treatment, first class? No. You'd have
to get on your hands and knees and beg
for home confinement. Oh, man. Uh
okay. So, let's see. We answered We
answered that. Democrats
Anal Ape says Democrats and Republicans
want us to care about social issues
because it doesn't affect their donors.
True. Uh Cooper Duper, what about um
Jasmine Crockett's Senate ad? How does
that speak to anyone?
>> And Allred dropped out.
Yeah.
>> Just yesterday I said, oh, it's going to
be a big fight. Allred's the stronger
candidate. He dropped out. And he's he
announced he's going to run for the
House of Representatives again. My
fellow Daytonian Sammy Land
again, the problem with Democrat
platform is that it's not honest.
Example, transhumanism. Most don't even
understand what that is. Yeah, I don't
know what the [__] that is. That's like
intersectionality. Who [__] knows
what that means? Nobody. It's like uh
you know, go
go into your Jacques Derrida collection
and look that up. Um Kevin Cronin, PBS
and NPR do not represent the Democratic
voters. Fair. Question for both of us
from Ali, uh does this lacking does the
Democrats lacking a message and
distrusting Republicans not leave enough
of a gap for a third party to come in?
Uh you would think. You would think that
it would.
I was talking to a a group of people
last night about this exact uh issue.
And and Ted, I repeated what you and I
had said that as recently as 100 years
ago, we had a half a dozen viable
national parties in this country. Mhm.
And with so many people with actually a
plurality of Americans now describing
themselves as independent,
in my view, that opens the door for two
political parties, one on the right and
one on the left. Yeah, there's a place
for left-wing progressive Democrats and
there's a place for America First
Republicans.
>> That's right. Uh
cuz the even with other Donald Trump,
the Republican Party is is controlled by
the corporatists. Sure, it is. We have
two corporatist parties.
Um You know, John, and they're lackeys
like Lindsey Graham.
>> My theory here is that the problem that
with third parties in recent decades has
been that they've all had a national
strategy, right? They've all their
theory has always been
let's just run someone for president and
then it'll trickle down and we'll run
people for Congress and later.
>> Exactly. It's the opposite. Right.
Because that because that can't work
because of the Electoral College.
Because the Electoral College is set up
you have to have 270 votes to win the
presidency. Even if you if third party
candidate had 70% of the popular vote,
he or she would still lose because of
the Electoral College and it would go to
the House of Representatives and either
the D's or the R's would vote for their
own team. That's right. It has to be
from the grassroots. And those parties
that you mentioned, John, from 100 years
ago, including but not limited to the
Prohibition Party, the Socialist Party,
uh Socialist Labor Party and so on, they
all the Populist Party, they all they
were all grassroots parties. They ran
people for Congress as alderman and so
on.
That's exactly right. Yeah, I I used to
joke that
when I was doing my little dance with
the Libertarians, I would get these
hair-on-fire emails like, oh my god, we
just elected somebody to the water
commission of Anchorage, Alaska.
It's like, okay, well, that's a start,
but you need to run people in like every
congressional race,
every state legislative race. You got to
start at the bottom. The water
commission of Anchorage
is not going to do it for you.
No. But on the other hand, it's not a
terrible thing to just if you have, you
know, if you have a national strategy
and you have I mean, the Libertarian
Party
has been around a long time. Um
you know, I mean, they're one of the
better organized third parties.
Yeah, they are. Well, listen, I I always
make this joke, but it's it's funny
because it's true. I was invited to the
Libertarian Christmas party a few years
ago. And of course, being Libertarians,
they held it at the end of January cuz
they just could not get their act
together.
I I think I've mentioned this to you.
One of these days I'll be talking
>> cuz they're cheap and didn't want to pay
top dollar for the for the space.
>> It was in this townhouse in Alexandria,
Virginia.
>> nog. Oh, yeah.
Townhouse in Alexandria, Virginia, Old
Town. And we're all wearing hello, my
name is name tags. Of course.
>> And this guy looks at my name tag and he
says, oh, John,
I've been hoping I'd run into you. Uh
he's wearing his tag. He's the head of
the Libertarian Party for Virginia.
So, I said, oh, nice to meet you. And I
shook his hand. He said, listen, uh do
Do you want to run for governor? And I
said, absolutely not.
And he said, really? Why?
And I said, look, I like you guys.
You're all nice guys. But I know how
this is going to play out. I said, I'm
going to be completely out of pocket.
Nobody's going to raise any money for
me. And in the end, I'm going to get 2%
and I'm going to humiliate myself. And
everyone will make fun of you.
>> Yeah. I said, no, thanks.
>> And and the worst part is you I'll tell
you the worst part of it. If you did
that, in the middle of the night, you'd
have these weird thoughts like,
what if I could win? Right. Exactly. And
you can't.
>> Oh, listen, listen, listen.
When I was traveling with Gary Johnson,
Gary Gary was the governor of New Mexico
and he was the Libertarian nominee for
president in 20 16 and 2012. But this
was in 2016 and we were in the Upper
Peninsula of Michigan.
And his sister joined us at dinner one
night. He had given a speech. I was
traveling with him to introduce him at
all of the speeches. And so his sister
came to dinner with us that night and
she was running for Congress from that
that Upper Peninsula district. And so, I
said to her, just cuz I was trying to
make conversation, I said, did you see
the latest polls? The incumbent
Republican is only polling at like 40%
up here. That's how how unpopular he is.
And she goes like this. She goes,
I might actually win this thing.
And I thought to myself, no, that's not
my point. You're not going to win this
thing.
It's just that he's unpopular.
Right.
>> up getting 2%.
But it's not uncommon to delude yourself
into thinking that,
you know, lightning might strike and you
might actually win this thing. Although,
yeah, I mean, think about Donald Trump,
that great picture from the New New in
2016 when they if they captured the
entire family in the hotel suite and
they just announced that Trump is going
to win and to a man they all have this
the [__]
>> Yeah. kind of expression. I think I
mentioned to you that my next door my
old next door neighbor when I was still
married he was the White House pastry
chef.
And he told us that he was at the White
House when
when Trump went to meet Obama for the
first time. It was 4 days after the
election and he said Trump looked sick
and he looked scared.
Yeah.
>> never thought he was going to win. He
was only running to enhance his brand.
>> Exactly.
He's a dog who caught a car.
Yeah.
>> Oh boy. I mean honestly though I think
you should be scared if you win the
presidency no matter who you are.
>> Big job. Yeah. You really should be.
Uh thanks Glass and Candy Trans for the
definition. Transhumanism is when humans
start replacing parts of their bodies
with mechanical replacements. Something
as simple as simple as a pacemaker can
be called transhumanist. It has nothing
to do with social justice. I don't know.
I've heard I've heard liberals talk
about transhumanism too.
Um I don't know.
>> See
I I just learned something. I never
heard that before.
>> Me neither. Uh Caddy Catastrophe 2 any
thoughts of on ice in Minnesota?
I I don't know what that is. Well you
know the you know the the immigration
enforcement. Oh ICE. I'm sorry. I was
thinking cuz it's winter and it's
Minnesota.
Oh my god.
Immigration and Customs Enforcement.
>> Right. Thank you. Yeah. Don't worry. I'm
not completely as stupid as I sound.
Okay. Um
In Minnesota specifically yeah. My
brother and sister both lived in
Minnesota. My brother was there for 9
years. My sister was there for like 15
years. There are large communities of
Somalis and Hmong from Cambodia.
And Laos. And Laos large Lao
community.
Uh
I was unaware that
a lack of documentation was a problem up
there. I'm unaware of that too because
it seems to me like these people were
brought in especially the Hmong.
>> They were former CIA assets.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
They were working for the CIA or working
for the military and we brought them as
refugees. And correct me if I'm wrong
but
my understanding is that basically in
these refugee situations basically
everyone packs into a C-130.
They they land at whatever US Air Force
base they happen to land at and then
that's kind of like where you live.
That's
that's how Dayton ended up with a ton of
Vietnamese.
>> And and Bismarck North Dakota and St.
Louis with a ton of Kurds. Iraqi Kurds.
So random.
>> Exactly right.
Um
I I kind of I mean there's a certain
beauty to that it's but it's it's also
very strange. Um thanks for the for the
$10 from Unsung Pat. You're we'll sing
your praises. George Washington warned
against the dangers of political
factions in his farewell address.
Political parties could could become
potent engines of faction that that
could lead to the erosion of national
unity. It's true that the founding
fathers did not anticipate a republic
with political parties but they quickly
formed. That is true. By the 1800
election they were basically
what we see today.
Um they even had their own media outlets
and everything. I I just like this quote
and then we have to do another story.
HVDAK I will live in Montana and I will
marry a round American woman and raise
rabbits and she will cook them for me
and I will have a pickup truck maybe
even a recreational vehicle.
I think I've always thought about having
a recreational vehicle and just like
the commitment and the gas mileage are
like the reason I wouldn't do it but it
looks fun as [__] Um It does.
Okay so let's talk about this report out
of the New York Times. Well there's two
reports out of the New York Times. Let's
talk about the Afghan Zero Units. This
is more of your purview. So the United
States recruited maybe you can explain
what a Zero Unit is. These
under the old Karzai Ghani
administration that ruled Afghanistan
from under US occupation from '01 to
2021 um the local Afghans who were kind
of you know collaborators let's just say
were reported where served in the Zero
Units. Um some of them were brought to
the United States kind of like those
those Laos and the and the Hmong and all
those people. Um and they but they a lot
of them were really mistreated and
neglected upon arrival. At least four of
them have committed suicide. And now
Rakmanullah
Lakhanwal stands accused of shooting
two national guardsmen in DC. Basically
by all accounts he was mentally ill
um and I I mean for that reason alone he
should walk and and be institutionalized
but the thing is um apparently these
guys
they were when they call in for help
they're told oh we can't find you in
your in our computer. They don't get
work permits cuz their names are a
little bit misspelled. Um basically
we're not taking good care of them and
they're and they're really in a bad
state and I got to just say personally
uh when I was in Afghanistan in '01
I remember talking to people and they
thought the US was as the preeminent
superpower in the world would work
miracles. They would tell people would
say like oh now that the Americans are
here they're going to rebuild all our
highways. We're going to have
skyscrapers all over the place. We're
going to have everything is going to be
beautiful within months. The Afghans
just because their state was so bleak
they radically overestimated our degree
of competence and our ability to do
things efficiently. And I was like no no
no no you don't understand. I'm from a
city that can't build 1 mile of subway
tunnel at all. Okay like we can't do
anything. It's not going to be like
that. I was trying to just explain how
slow and dysfunctional the US government
can be. Anyway I just wonder if that
feeds into the psychology here these
Afghans like I've made it to the
promised land and the the gap between
that level of expectation and the
reality
you know basically made them crack. I
think that it's darker than that. Tell
me. I think that
you get recruited into
not just the CIA but this very specific
CIA unit.
And they start taking you out in the
middle of the night to do raids and to
kill your fellow tribesmen.
Right? People who are members of your
extended family just because the CIA
disagrees with them politically.
You're given no training. You're given
no treatment no therapy no nothing. Just
come with us and shoot that guy.
And it's enough to make people crazy.
You know most people
can't take the pressure of of committing
serial murder which is really what it
comes down to or mass murder.
And
then we say oh don't worry we're going
to bring you to the United States and
it's going to be the land of milk and
honey and you're going to be fine. If
you need it you can get therapy.
And then they move into what you just
described.
There's nothing efficient about the
United States. There's no therapy that's
being given. There's no work permit.
There's no nothing. We throw them into
this country where they barely speak the
language if they speak it at all. They
can't work. They don't know anybody.
They're completely out of their element.
Can you imagine leaving the the Afghan
desert and then ending up in let's say
Denver? What the heck are you going to
do? It's it's got to be it's just kind
of make your mind explode.
>> Yeah. And and then at the same time the
US government has just turned its back
on you and they tell you well you're on
your own.
Yeah. That's and I guess many of them
also are losing certainly members of
their extended family right? Yeah. We
basically turn long extended families
which is common to Afghans into a
nuclear family and that's also a culture
shock. Very quickly the New York Times
says that the Trump administration
uh is having trouble figuring out what
to do with these survivors of these drug
boat drone attacks in the southern
Caribbean. There was thought of sending
them to El Salvador to that prison the
Secot prison but um that was ruled out.
And basically the problem is here's the
thing that gets me John. Uh the
administra administration officials are
admitting that they don't want to try
these people through the courts cuz if
they do the legality of the attacks is
going to come into question. The
rationale is going to come into
question. But I'm like if we're going
after drug traffickers isn't the main
point to arrest them and then threaten
them with charges and find out who their
bosses are? And speaking of which the
Washington Post is reporting right now
that the House Armed Services Committee
is ending its probe into the boat
strike. Uh so we will never get answers
to those questions Ted.
So that yeah I was trying to read
between the tea leaves. Does that mean
like the it's over go home nothing to
see here or does it mean we've finished
our inquiry and you can expect a report
from us later on?
>> No report. They've only been inquiring
for 3 or 4 days.
You would need you know 6 months
for your investigation to do the to do
the investigation. No. The White House
put pressure on Republicans in Congress
specifically on that weak jellyfish Mike
Johnson.
And so there will be no investigation
into the boat strikes.
Ridiculous.
Um John thanks for joining me as always
always look forward to these mornings
with you.
We are back here with the program. Scott
Stantis from the Chicago Tribune will be
filling in for John tomorrow Thursday
9:00 a.m. Eastern Time. Friday John will
be back 9:00 a.m. Eastern Time. It's all
call in time. So be articulate be pithy
be short as Robbie suggests. Please stay
tuned to the TMI show with me and
Milania Chan. That's coming up at 10:00
Eastern time. In other words, just in a
minute or two. If
bear in mind Friday's show, just to
remind you, is a Rumble exclusive. Only
Rumble, not YouTube. No YouTube, only
Rumble. Thanks everyone. Bye John.
Bye-bye.
[Music]